Contact

443-850-8317 (Mobile) eyado0605@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/eyad-abdel-latif-1bb74834 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Public Health

Healthcare Management

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Modeling Courageous Leadership: Intelligent Disobedience

Building Resilience

Managing Generation Z

Managing Stress

Eyad Abdel Latif

Director of Nursing Acute Care Services at Novant Health UVA Health System Prince William and Haymarket Medical Centers Falls Church, Virginia

Summary

A nurse leader with 20 years of hospital based clinical experience both national and international, nine of which are in nursing leadership. I am servant leader focused on relationship building to achieve outcomes. Focused on forging multi professional partnership, an inclusionary mindset as people support what they help create, I was successful in leading teams to achieve care excellence in a fast-paced healthcare environment.

Experience

Novant Health UVA Health System Prince William Medical Center Director of Nursing Acute Care Services April 2020 - Present (4 months)

Manassas, Virginia, United States

Inova Fairfax Medical Campus Specialty Clinical Director October 2015 - October 2019 (4 years 1 month) Virginia

MedStar Georgetown University Hospital 7 years 1 month

Clinical Administrator February 2010 - October 2015 (5 years 9 months)

Critical Care Registered Nurse - Neuroscience ICU October 2008 - February 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center Registered Nurse - Progressive Care Unit March 2006 - October 2008 (2 years 8 months) King Abdulaziz Medical City
Critical Care Registered Nurse - Trauma ICU
July 2002 - December 2005 (3 years 6 months)

American University of Beirut Medical Center Critical Care Registered Nurse - ICU October 1999 - July 2002 (2 years 10 months)

Education

Johns Hopkins School of Nursing

Master's Degree, Master of Science in Nursing - Health Systems Management
(HSM) · (2008 - 2013)

The Johns Hopkins University - Carey Business School Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Business Administration and Management, General · (2008 - 2013)

American University of Beirut
Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1995 - 1999)